Guide to the Herbert Matter Papers
Department of Special Collections
Herbert Matter papers
ca. 1937-1984
M1446
Matter, Herbert, 1907-1984
ca. 310 linear feet
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Original artwork, photographs, letters, manuscripts, process materials, memorabilia, negatives, transparencies, film, printed material, and working equipment.
Access
Collection is open for research; materials must be requested at least 24 hours in advance of intended use.
Acquisition Information
Purchased, 2004: accession 2004-283. Gift of the Matter family, 2005: accession 2005-114 (Series nine, 300 photographic prints.)
Biography / Administrative History
Born in the resort village of Engelberg, Switzerland, Herbert Matter is best known for his international contributions in photography, photomontage, and graphic design work. Matter was also a filmmaker, exhibition designer, and professor. He photographed a wide range of subjects in art, advertising, and fashion. His constant experimenting lead to ongoing refinements in composition, typography, and a variety of printing techniques.
Matter initially studied painting at the Ëcole des Beaux-Arts in Geneva and then at the Académie Moderne in Paris as a student of Fernand Léger, and Amédée Ozenfant.
He came to the United States in 1936 and began work as a freelance photographer for Harper's Bazaar and Vogue magazines and the Museum of Modern Art in New York, and created displays for the Swiss and Corning Glass Pavilions for the 1939 World's Fair.
Over the course of his career Matter worked with Charles Eames, did photography, photomontage, and covers for Arts and Architecture magazine, and served as the design and advertising consultant for Knoll creating the company's award winning graphics, layout, and photography.
He also directed, filmed, and edited Works of Calder in 1950 for the Museum of Modern Art, the first color film to show Alexander Calder's sculptures. While maintaining countless assignments, he introduced the first photography classes offered at Yale University where he taught until 1976.
Matter's most personal artistic endeavor was his extensive photography of the work of sculpture Alberto Giacometti. These photographs from the 1960s and 1970s were published in his book Alberto Giacometti. Matter worked on the book up to the time of his death; it was published posthumously in 1987.
Scope and Content of Collection
The collection represents the photography and graphic design career of Herbert Matter, his commercial and personal work. This includes original artwork (collages, sketches), photographs (predominately black and white prints, contact prints, working prints), manuscripts, process materials (paste-ups, proof sheets), memorabilia, negatives, transparencies, slides, 16mm motion picture film, printed material, and working equipment. There is considerable correspondence with particularly noteworthy letters from Gregory Ain, John Cage, John Entenza, Walter Gropius, Gyorgy Kepes, Isamu Noguchi, Irving Penn, and Brett Weston among others. The core of the collection is contained in over 100 boxes of graphic art material. In addition, there are over 60 boxes containing photographs, negatives, and transparencies of his commercial and non-commercial photographic work.
Arrangement
The Matter collection is arranged in nine Series, with Subseries and Subsubseries augmenting the organizational structure.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Aalto, Aino, 1894-1949.; Aalto, Alvar, 1898-1976.; Abramovitz, Max.; Albers, Josef.; Albini, Franco.; Albinson, Don.; Archipenko, Alexander, 1887-1964.; Armstrong, Louis, 1901-1971.; Arp, Jean, 1887-1966.; Austin, Warren.; Bacon, Francis, 1909-; Ballard, Shreve.; Barnes, Edward Larrabee.; Barnes, Mary, 1923-; Baziotes, William, 1912-1963.; Beckstrand, Mildred.; Bennett, Glen.; Berry, James.; Bertoia, Harry.; Boeri, Cini.; Bontecou, Lee, 1931-; Bossard, Klaus.; Botticelli, Sandro, 1444 or 5-1510.; Brancusi, Constantin, 1876-1957.; Braque, Georges, 1882-1963.; Burri, Alberto, 1915-; Butler, Lewis.; Cafiero, Vincent.; Cajori, Charles, 1921-.; Calder, Alexander, 1898-1976.; Calder, Alexander Stirling, 1870-1945.; Calder, Louisa.; Callery, Mary, 1903-1977.; Carles, Arthur B., 1882-1952.; Cassandre, A. M., 1901-1968.; Cézanne, Paul, 1839-1906.; Chagall, Marc, 1887-; Chillida, Eduardo, 1924-; Clayton, Buck, 1911-; Cohen, I. David, (Isidore David), 1884-1953.; Cohen, John.; Cohen, Penny.; Cordoba, Mathilde de.; Crawford, Joan, 1908-1977.; Dale, Chester, b.1883.; De Chirico, Giorgio, 1888-; de Cordoba, Mathilde.; De Kooning, Elaine.; De Kooning, Willem, 1904-; de Souza-Gomez, H.; Defucio, Robert.; Dehn, Mura.; Dorn, Marion V.; Dragonette, Jessica.; Duchamp-Villon, Raymond, 1876-1918.; Dudley, George A.; Dufay, Guillaume, 1474.; Eames, Charles.; Eames, Lucia.; Eames, Ray.; Eldon, Jim.; Feldman, Irving, 1928-; Feldman, Morton, 1926-1987.; Ferrari-Hardoy, Jorge.; Finkelstein, Louis.; Forge, Andrew.; Frank, Joseph, 1918-; Frankenthaler, Helen, 1928-; Fuller, R. Buckminster (Richard Buckminster), 1895-; Gabo, Naum, 1890-1977.; Geldzahler, Henry.; Giacometti, Alberto, 1901-1966.; Giacometti, Annette.; Giacometti, Diego.; Gleizes, Albert, 1881-1953.; Goddard, Paulette.; Goldstone, Harmon H. (Harmon Hendricks), 1911-; Grosman, Tatvana, 1904-1982.; Guston, Philip, 1913-; Hannah, Bruce.; Harrison, Wallace K. (Wallace Kirkman), 1895-; Heifetz, Jascha, 1901-; Hess, Trudi.; Hirschorn, Joseph H.; Hoffman, Armin.; Hofmann, Hans, 1880-1966.; Jeanneret, Pierre, 1896-1965.; Jeanneret, Charles Edouard.; Johns, Jasper, 1930-; Kaiser, Ray.; Kelly, Richard.; Kiesler, Frederick.; Klein, Franz.; Knoll, Florence.; Knoll, Hans, 1890-.; Knoll, Peter.; Knorr, Donald.; Knox, Doris.; Krasner, Lee, 1908-; Lebeau, Roland.; Le Corbusier, 1887-1965.; Léger, Fernand, 1881-1955.; Lehmbruck, Wilhelm, 1881-1919.; Lescaze, William, 1896-1969.; Lichtenstein, Roy, 1923-; Little, John.; Loewy, Raymond, 1893-1986.; Logan, Joshua.; Lollo, Dizzy.; Maccio, Romulo, 1931-.; Maclanchlen, Betty.; Magritte, René, 1898-1967.; Mangiarotti, Angelo.; Mathsson, Bruno.; Matisse, Pierre, 1900-1989.; Matta Echaurren, Roberto Sebastian, 1911-.; Matter, Alex.; Matter, Herbert.; Matter, Jordan.; Matter, Mercedes.; McGray, Peter.; McGray, Porter.; Meredith, Burgess, 1908-; Miró, Joan, 1893-; Mies van der Rohe, Ludwig, 1886-1969.; Mondrian, Piet, 1872-1944.; Moore, Henry, 1898-; Morgan, Willard Detering, 1900-.; Morris, George L.K.; Morrison, Andrew.; Motherwell, Robert.; Muller, Henry, 1902-.; Muller, Jan.; Nagy, Laszlo Moholy.; Nakashima, George, 1905-; Nast, Condé, 1873-1942.; Nehru, Jawaharlal, 1889-1964.; Nelson, Paul.; Newman, Barnett, 1905-1970.; Niemeyer, Oscar.; Nitschke, Oscar.; O'Hara, Frank.; Olson, Odelberg.; Ormandy, Eugene, 1899-1985.; Oswald, Marion.; Pearson, L. Max, 1886-.; Pearstein, Philip.; Petit, Don.; Pevsner, Antoine, 1886-1962.; Picasso, Pablo, 1881-1973.; Picchetti, Carlo.; Platner, Warren, 1919-; Pollock, Charles.; Pollock, Jackson, 1912-1956.; Rae, Christine.; Rand, Paul, 1914-; Rassmussen, Jorgen.; Rauschenberg, Robert, 1925-; Rebetez, Robert.; Risom, Jens.; Ritchard, Cyril, 1897-1977.; Rivers, Larry, 1925-; Rosenquist, James.; Rothko, Mark.; Rudolph, Paul, 1898-1976.; Saarinen, Eero, 1910-1961.; Sandals, Bernardo.; Scarpa, Tobia.; Schlossberg, Edwin.; Schultz, Richard.; Seitlin, Percy.; Senft, Peter.; Sert, José Luis, 1902-; Sillman, Ives.; Sorenson, Abel.; Southern, Terry.; Stephens, Bill.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Stone, Edward Durrell.; Sweeney, Ciannait.; Sweeney, James Johnson, 1900-; Switzerland, Christian.; Sylvester, David.; Takahama, Kazuhide.; Tamayo, Ruffino.; Tàpies, Antoni, 1923-; Tapiovaara, Ilmari.; Temple, Shirley, 1928-; Thackray, Joanna.; Thompson, David C.; Twombly, Cy, 1928-; Vicente, Esteban, 1903-; Vincente, Harriet.; Waddell, Theodore.; Wagner, Hans, 1929-; Weese, Harry.; Wegner, Hans.; Wolff, Robert.; Wormley, Edward.; Wright, Frank Lloyd, 1867-1959.; Wyler, Eva.; Zapf, Otto.; Zogbaum, Wilfrid, 1915-1965.; Zumstag, Abraham.; Arts et métiers graphiques.; American Institute of Graphic Arts.; Black Star (Picture agency); Bonwit Teller & Co.; Boston and Maine Railroad.; Coca-Cola Company.; Condé Nast Publications, Inc.; Consolidated Edison Company of New York, Inc.; Container Corporation of America.; Corning Glass Works.; Cummins Engine Company.; Deberny et Peignot.; First Savings. (Houston, Tex.); Ives - Sillman Workshop.; Kimbe Optic.; Knoll Associates, Inc.; Kunsthaus Zürich.; Metropolitan Museum of Art (New York, N.Y.); Mount Washington Ski Resort (Plymouth, New Hampshire); Museum of Fine Arts, Houston.; Museum of Modern Art (New York, N.Y.); Museum of Primitive Art (New York, N.Y.); New Bauhaus (Chicago, Ill.); New York, New Haven, and Hartford Railroad Company.; New York Studio School.; Oxford Paper Company.; Pepsi-Cola Company.; Schweizerische Zentrale für Verkehrsförderung.; Seagram Company.; Solomon R. Guggenheim Museum.; Seven-Up Company.; Tishman Construction Corporation.; Union Carbide Corporation.; Universal Limited Art Editions.; Westinghouse Electric Corporation.; Wyandotte Chemicals.; Yale University.; African American dance.; Art, Modern--Switzerland.; Art, Modern--20th century.; Civil Defense.; Dance.; Design.; Furniture--United States--History.; Graphic arts.; New York World's Fair (1939-1940).; Photography, Artistic.; Sculpture, Modern--20th century.; Colonial Williamsburg (Williamsburg, Va.); Coney Island (New York, N.Y.); Grosse Pointe (Mich.). Library.
Index Terms Related to this Collection
Ain, Gregory, 1908-; Baldwin, Benjamin.; Beebe, Tina.; Bill, Max, 1908-; Breuer, Connie.; Breuer, Marcel, 1902-; Bunshaft, Gordon, 1909-; Cage, John.; Chermayeff, Serge, 1900-; Dearstyne, Howard.; Entenza, John, 1903-; Girard, Alexander.; Gropius, Walter, 1883-1969.; Johnson, Philip, 1906-; Kendrick, Marvin.; Kepes, Gyorgy, 1906-; Larsen, Jack Lenor.; Liberman, Alexander, 1912-; Lord, James.; Noguchi, Isamu, 1904-; Penn, Irving.; Prestini, James.; Salzman, Arthur George.; Vignelli, Massimo.; Weston, Brett.; Yanaihara, Isaku, 1918-.; Ouro Preto (Minas Gerais, Brazil); Arts & architecture.; Fortune Magazine.; Harpers Bazaar.; House & Garden.; House Beautiful.; Ladies Home Journal.; Mademoiselle.; PLUS.; Vogue.
- Series 1: Biographical, 21 linear ft.
  This series provides details related to Matter's professional life such as his CV (Curriculum vitae), publications featuring his work, awards and certificates, documents including passports, IDs, and material related to exhibitions of Matter's photography and graphic design. Prints and negatives of Matter and his family are in this series along with notes, and written ideas about photography.
  - Subseries 1.01: Resumes
    - Subsubseries 1.01.01: CV (Curriculum Vitae)
      - Resumes and CV; [Folder 1 of 2].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 1)
      - Resumes and CV; [Folder 2 of 2].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 2)
    - Subsubseries: 1.01.02 Guggenheim Fellowship
      - Guggenheim Fellowship; [Folder 1 of 5].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 3)
      - Guggenheim Fellowship; [Folder 2 of 5].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 4)
      - Guggenheim Fellowship; [Folder 3 of 5].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 5)
      - Guggenheim Fellowship; [Folder 4 of 5].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 6)
      - Guggenheim Fellowship; [Folder 5 of 5].ND, Original writings: typed papers (Box 248, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 1.02: Inventory of Work
    - Inventory of Work.ND, Handwritten and typed papers: photocopy prints. (Box 248, Folder 8)
    - Photocopies of glass plate negatives (series 3, subseries 8).ND, Photocopy prints. (Box 428, Folder 9)
    - Former archive documents - Yale University.ND, Typed inventory lists:handwritten notes on label. (Box 428, Folder 10)
    - Photocopies of work from House and Garden magazine covers from 1948-1953; [Folder 1 of 2].ND, Photocopies of cover art. (Box 428, Folder 11)
    - Photocopies of work from House and Garden magazine covers from 1947-1953; [Folder 2 of 2].ND, Photocopies of cover art. (Box 428, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 1.03: Profiled Work
    - Exhibition Catalogs - "Symbols Signs Logos Trademarks by Herbert Matter"., Color 5 1/2"x8" booklets: 24 pp. (Othertype 183)
    - Brochure "7 Swiss Photographers" (1979)., Silver 9"x3 3/4" folded brochure. (Box 187, Folder 1)
    - Giacometti announcement brochure; Ives-Sillman., b/w 6"x 7 1/4" brochure with photographs. (Box 187, Folder 2)
    - Graphis 212 (1980/1981)., Color cover with b/w pages: 9 1/4"x11 3/4" brochure. (Box 187, Folder 3)
    - Exhibition Catalogs - American Institute of Graphic Arts (AIGA 1962)., b/w brochure with red ink: vellum cover: 8"x12". (Box 187, Folder 4)
    - A4 architects and designers diary (1985)., Calender book with black cloth cover: b/w with red ink pages: 8 1/2"x12". Original boxes included. (Box 187, Folder 5)
    - Publications and published work - Matter [1 of 2]., Catalogs: books. (Othertype 217)
      The School of Art at Yale; Un Pueple D'affirme; A4 Architects and Designers Diary 1985; The Brickbuilder Architectural Forum; Applied Photography, Graphis 212; Graphis 22; Graphis 60; Art News; America Calling; Bride's Magazine; Fortune; Luzerner Neuste Nachricten magazin; Vogue
    - Publications and published work - Matter [2 of 2]., Pamphlets: magazines: clippings. (Othertype 219)
      Interlaken; Schweiz Suisse Svizzera Switzerland; Photographie; Norte Revista Continental; The Photographer and The Artist; Schweizer Photographen von 1840 bis heute; LNN Magazin; Arts et metiers Graphiques 51; Graphis 212; Die Berner Woche; Visual Arts Bulletin; Zurcher Illustrierte; The Art and Technique of Color Photography 1951; Vogue
    - Copy Negatives of images appearing in Pollock Matters exhibition catalog; Published by Abrams, 2006; [Folder 1 of 2]., b/w, color 4"x5" (Box 436, Folder 17)
    - Copy Negatives of images appearing in Pollock Matters exhibition catalog; Published by Abrams, 2006; [Folder 2 of 2]., b/w, color 4"x5". (Box 436, Folder 18)
  - Subseries 1.04: Family Negatives, Slides, Transparencies
    - Turkey; horses., b/w 35mm negatives. (Box 186, Folder 1)
    - Henry Muller Farm., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 2)
    - Italian vacation., Color 2 1/4" transparencies. (Box 186, Folder 3)
    - "Jeany's wedding"., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 4)
    - Barnes, Edward Larrabee; Includes Joseph Albers., b/w half frame and 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 5)
      Also includes Joseph Albers
      Albers, Joseph
    - Matter; Alex "Pundy"; Knoll, Hans and Florence (1951)., b/w 35 mm negatives. (Box 186, Folder 6)
    - Bethlehem house exterior., Color 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 7)
    - "Karen Guttman"., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 8)
    - Herbert and Mercedes' wedding., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 9)
    - Mercedes as a child., b/w and color 35 mm slides. (Box 186, Folder 10)
    - Mercedes Matter's childhood., b/w negatives: various sizes. (Box 186, Folder 11)
    - Matter, Alex "Pundy"; [1 of 2]., Color 35 mm slides. (Box 186, Folder 12)
    - Matter, Alex "Pundy"; [2 of 2]., b/w half frame negatives. (Box 186, Folder 13)
    - Family cats and dog., Color 2 1/4" transparencies. (Box 186, Folder 14)
    - MacDougal alley exterior., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 15)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter drawing., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 16)
    - Senft, Peter; Matter, Alex "Pundy"; Switzerland, Christian., Color 2 1/4" transparencies. (Box 186, Folder 17)
    - Matter, Alex "Pundy"; Bethlehem., Color 2 1/4" transparencies. (Box 186, Folder 18)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with Cartree (Knoll dog)., Color 2 1/4" transparencies. (Box 186, Folder 19)
    - Mercedes Matter on Eames property before construction., b/w 4"x5" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 20)
      Eames, Charles
    - Bethlehem exteriors., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 21)
    - Maine house exterior., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 22)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter in butterfly chair, b/w 35 mm negatives. (Box 186, Folder 23)
    - San Francisco., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 24)
    - John Little house., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 25)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with candle (1944)., b/w 4"x5" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 26)
    - Mercedes Matter shot with "big telescope"., b/w 4"x5" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 27)
    - East Point, Maine., Color 2 1/4" transparencies. (Box 186, Folder 28)
    - "Pianist friend of Christina Rae"., b/w 35 mm negatives. (Box 186, Folder 29)
    - Matter Studio with Giacometti Sculpture., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 30)
    - Herbert Matter studio interior with artwork by others., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 31)
    - Camera on track with outdoor setting (not Alexander Calder related)., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 186, Folder 32)
    - Mercedes Matter, Alexander "Pundy" Matter with Lee Krasner, Jackson Pollock sitting together outdoors., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Box 436, Folder 22)
      Pollock, Jackson; Krasner, Lee; Matter, Mercedes
  - Subseries 1.05: Family Prints
    - Matter, Alex "Pundy"., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 1)
    - Hans; Florence and Peter Knolls; others unidentified., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 2)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with baseball glove., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 3)
    - Italian vacation., b/w prints. 2 1/4": 8"x10" contact prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 4)
    - McDougal alley exteriors., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 5)
    - Mercedes Matter obituary., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 6)
    - Ciannait Sweeney (James Johnson Sweeney's daughter)., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 7)
    - "Jeany"., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 8)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with candle., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 9)
    - Matter, Jordan., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 10)
    - Family dog (interior)., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 11)
    - Herschler (cousin)., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 12)
    - Matter family in Switzerland., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 13)
    - Mercedes Matter; Alex "Pundy" Matter with DeCordoba family., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 14)
    - Matter's mother., b/w prints. (Oversize 222, Folder 15)
    - Matter, Mercedes., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 1)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with Herbert Matter ice skating., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 2)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with Mercedes Matter in California., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 3)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter birthday party; beach., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 4)
    - Unidentified boy in row boat., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 5)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter on Eames Elephant; Eames., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 6)
    - Eames, Lucia., b/w prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 7)
    - Alex "Pundy" Matter with pet goat and other children., b/w prints: contact prints from half frame. (Oversize 438, Folder 8)
    - Portrait taken by photographer at Parthenon restaurant in New York; Photograph was not taken by Herbert Matter; Group portrait includes Mercedes Matter, Marcel and Connie Breuer, Alexander Calder, Hans Knoll, and other unidentified people.ND, b/w 4 1/2"x6 1/2" print inside a cardboard frame 6 1/2"x8 1/2" with blue logo of Parthenon restaurant. (Oversize 438, Folder 9)
    - Alexander Calder and family; Pollock, Jackson; Krasner, Lee; Matter, Mercedes; Matter, Alex "Pundy"; All are at the beach.ND, b/w half frame contact prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 10)
    - Photograph of Herbert Matter painting.ND, b/w print. (Oversize 438, Folder 11)
    - Herbert Matter family with Charles and Ray Eames on beach.1943 ca., b/w 2 1/4" contact prints. (Oversize 438, Folder 12)
  - Subseries 1.06: Negatives, Slides, Transparencies
    - H; Matter; Outside; coat and tie., b/w 4"x5" negatives. (Othertype 230, Folder 1)
    - H; Matter; Portraits., Color 35 mm slides. (Othertype 230, Folder 2)
    - H; Matter; Studio with Christina Rae; Re: Knoll., b/w 8"x10" transparencies. (Othertype 230, Folder 3)
    - H; Matter; Studio - desk., Color 2 1/4" negatives. (Othertype 230, Folder 4)
    - H; Matter; 1949 - at desk., b/w 8"x10" transparencies. (Othertype 230, Folder 5)
    - H; Matter; early., b/w 2 1/4": 4"x5" negatives. (Othertype 230, Folder 6)
    - H; Matter; Tie and jacket., b/w 35 mm negatives. (Othertype 230, Folder 7)
    - H; Matter; Studio clouds., Color 8"x10" transparencies. (Othertype 230, Folder 8)
    - H; Matter; Outside., Color 2 1/4" negatives. (Othertype 230, Folder 9)
    - H; Matter; Mamiya camera., b/w 2 1/4" negatives. (Othertype 230, Folder 10)
    - H; Matter; Womb chair., b/w 8"x10" transparencies. (Othertype 230, Folder 11)
    - H; Matter; Profile., b/w 8"x10" transparencies. (Othertype 230, Folder 12)
    - H; Matter; Self portrait - strobe., b/w 8"x10" transparencies. (Othertype 230, Folder 13)
  - Subseries 1.07: Exhibition Photographs, Catalogs, Announcements
    - Subsubseries 1.07.01 Stanford Matter Exhibition
      - Niche panels; [Tube 1 of 2]., Panels. (Othertype 455)
      - Niche panels; [Tube 2 of 2]., Panels. (Othertype 456)
      - Rotunda panels; [Tube 1 of 2]., Panels. (Othertype 457)
      - Rotunda panels; [Tube 2 of 2]., Panels. (Othertype 458)
      - Facsimile and enlarged prints (from all cases); [Map Folder 1 of 2]., various prints. (Othertype 459)
      - Facsimile and enlarged prints (from all cases); [Map Folder 2 of 2]., various prints. (Othertype 460)
      - Display Case 1; [Folder 1 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 1)
      - Display Case 2; [Folder 2 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 2)
      - Display Case 3; [Folder 3 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 3)
      - Display Case 4; [Folder 4 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 4)
      - Display Case 5; [Folder 5 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 5)
      - Display Case 6; [Folder 6 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 6)
      - Display Case 7; [Folder 7 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 7)
      - Display Case 8; [Folder 8 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 8)
      - Display Case 9; [Folder 9 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 9)
      - Display Case 10; [Folder 10 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 10)
      - Display Case 11; [Folder 11 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 11)
      - Display Case 12; [Folder 12 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 12)
      - Display Case 13; [Folder 13 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 13)
      - Display Case 14; [Folder 14 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 14)
      - Display Case 15; [Folder 15 of 24]; Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 15)
      - Display Case 16; [Folder 16 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 16)
      - Display Case 17; [Folder 17 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 17)
      - Display Case 18; [Folder 18 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 18)
      - Display Case 19; [Folder 19 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 19)
      - Display Case 20; [Folder 20 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 20)
      - Display Case 21; [Folder 21 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 21)
      - Display Case 22; [Folder 22 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 22)
      - Display Case 23; [Folder 23 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 23)
      - Display Case 24; [Folder 24 of 24]; [Box 1 of 2]. (Oversize 461, Folder 24)
      - Display Case 1; [Folder 1 of 24]; [Box 2 of 2]. (Oversize 462, Folder 1)
      - Display Case 2; [Folder 2 of 24]; [Box 2 of 2]. (Oversize 462, Folder 2)